Guide to the Ansel Adams Papers, 1932-1984.
Department of Special Collections
Ansel Adams Papers,
1932-1984.
Special Collections M359
Waters, George,; Adams, Ansel
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Provenance:
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. George Waters, 1983 and 1984.
Access Restrictions:
None
Biographical Note:
Friend and business associate of American photographer Ansel Adams, George Waters corresponded with Adams over a period of almost forty years. Waters supervised the photolithography work for many of Adams' publications; the correspondence reflects both Adams' and Waters' attention to detail and the creation of fine reproductions.
Scope and Contents Note:
Correspondence is arranged chronologically, with letters from Adams and Waters interfiled. Incoming correspondence to Waters from others, primarily concerning the production of Adams' books, follows the Adams-Waters correspondence. Subject files for the books Waters worked on are arranged alphabetically by title of book.
There are awards, keepsakes, and reproductions of Adams' photographs, as well as two Adams photographs by George Waters of Ansel Adams, 1946-1947, 1974, and 1979. Ephemeral publications and objects including a tee-shirt and coffee can decorated with Adams' photos complete the collection.
Container Listing
- Series 1. Correspondence, 1954-1973
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ansel Adams-George Waters, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Incoming correspondence to Waters from others, 1964-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 2. Subject files, 1971-1979
  - Clarence Kennedy Photographs, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of the Southwest, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of the Southwest, photographic record, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Polaroid Land Manual, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Taos (facsimile), 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yosemite and the Range of Light, 1978 April -1978 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yosemite and the Range of Light, 1978 Sept. -1978 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yosemite and the Range of Light, 1979 Jan. -1979 July (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Yosemite and the Range of Light, photographic record, [ca. 1979 July 30] (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series 3. Photographs
  - 1 polaroid portrait each of Adams and Waters. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ansel and Virginia Adams on a trip to Mojave Desert and the Grand Canyon taken by Waters, 1946-1947. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series 4. Awards, Keepsakes, Reproductions
  - Award, American Institute of Graphic Arts, Images 1923-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions and keepsakes, photolithography by George Waters. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series 5. Publications, Photolithography by George Waters
  - "Don Wort: Photographs 1956-1972", introduction by Ansel Adams. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Photographs by Clarence Kennedy", portrait and technical advice by Ansel Adams. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Polaroid Corporation, 1978", Adams and Kennedy photographs. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series 6. Other Publications
  - "A chance to be involved", National Park Foundation, photographs by Ansel Adams. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles about Adams (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Articles by Adams, (Fortnightly Review, 1932) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 7. Miscellany
  - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tee-shirt, "Photographs of the Southwest." (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hills Bros. coffee can with an Ansel Adams photograph (Box 3)